Inventory to the Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1970-1979
University of Virginia, Arthur J. Morris Law Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
Addition to the Papers of Hardy Cross Dillard 1970-1979
Special Collections, University of Virginia Law Library
MSS 84-8a
This collection consists of 12 boxes.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
This addition to the Hardy Cross Dillard papers was given to the Law Library by his widow Valgerdur Dillard, in February 1987.
Scope and Content Information
The 12 boxes contain files of Hardy Cross Dillard's work as judge on the International Court of Justice from 1970 to 1979. Significant materials besides the case files include 20 folders of personal correspondence, speeches and writings.
Contents List
- Beagle Channel Arbitration (BCA): Correspondence 1970-1978, 6 folders (Box 65)
- BCA: Handwritten notes on Verbatim Record [1976] (Box 66)
- BCA: HCD's memoranda [notes and final copies] [1976] (Box 66)
- BCA: HCD's memoranda and response [1976] (Box 66)
- BCA: Notes and research material n.d., 2 folders (Box 66)
- BCA: Memoranda and other documents compiled by Court of Arbitration 1971-76, n.d. (Box 66)
- BCA: Printed research material 1975, n.d. (Box 67)
- BCA: Notes on the case in the form of questions n.d. (Box 67)
- BCA: Notes on cartography n.d. (Box 67)
- BCA: Documents presented by Argentina and Chile 1974-76, 4 folders (Box 67)
- BCA: Verbatim Records 1974, Nov. 29 (Box 68)
- BCA: Verbatim Records annotated by HCD 1976 Sept. 8--Oct. 23, 10 folders (Box 68-69)
- BCA: [Drafts of the Decision] n.d. (Box 69)
- Charter of the United Nations with Statute of the International Court of Justice and Rules of Court, with annotations by HCD n.d. (Box 70)
- F. R. G. v. Iceland: Application, Memorials and Reports 1972-73 (Box 70)
- GEN. 70/27, 70/27 bis, 70/27 ter, 70/41, 71/12, 78/38 1970-71, -78 (Box 70)
- Greece v. Turkey (GT): GT 76/15, 76/16, 78/1, 78/4, 78/5 1976, 1978 (Box 70)
- 78/10-13, 78/15-19, 78/29, 78/35-39, 78/46; Memorial of Greece (Box 70)
- GT: C.R. 76/1-3, 78/1-7, 1976, 1978, 3 folders (Box 70-71)
- GT: Reports and Judgments 1976, 1977 (Box 71)
- GT: Memoranda 1975, n.d. (Box 71)
- India v. Pakistan (IP): I.P. 72/5, 72/49 (in Fr.), C.R. 72/7 (verbatim record) 1972 (Box 71)
- IP: Application Instituting Proceedings and Reports 1973 (Box 71)
- IP: Memoranda n.d. (Box 71)
- Interim Protective Orders: Notes n.d. (Box 71)
- Namibia Case: Request for Advisory Opinion 1970 (Box 71)
- NAM. 70/4, 71/30, 71/50, 71/52 1971 (Box 71)
- Namibia: Memoranda n.d. (Box 71)
- Nuclear Test Cases: Applications for Permission to Intervene and Reports of Judgements 1973 (Box 71)
- Nuclear: ANZ 73/85, 74/50 1974 (Box 71)
- Nuclear: Memoranda n.d. (Box 71)
- P.V. 71/19, 72/32, 75/1, 76/9, 77/3, 77/14, 77/19, 77/21 1971-77 (Box 71)
- R.J. 73/11, 73/19, 73/24, 73/43 [re U.N. Administrative Tribunal] 1973 (Box 71)
- RR 75/1, 75/3, 76/15, 76/15 bis, 76/16, 76/17, 77/6, 77/7, 77/9, 77/13 bis, 77/16, 77/17 1976-77 (Box 72)
- Rules Revision Committee--Working Documents 77/32, 77/50 1977 (Box 72)
- Rules Revision Committee--Memoranda and Correspondence 1974-75 (Box 72)
- U.K. and Ireland v. Iceland: Reports 1972-73 (Box 72)
- U.K. ...: Memoranda 1973-74 (Box 72)
- U.K. ...: AI 74/37, 74/16, and BI 74/12, 74/13 1974 (Box 72)
- Western Sahara Case: Memoranda 1975 (Box 72)
- Documents re various topics (some informal memoranda by HCD) 1970-80 (Box 72)
- Miscellaneous memoranda 1973, 1975, n.d. (Box 72)
- Miscellaneous research material n.d. (Box 72)
- Book review by Oscar Schacter with notes by HCD c. 1977 (Box 72)
- "Crank Mail" sent to HCD at The Hague c. 1970-79, 2 folders (Box 72)
- Personal Correspondence 1940-45, 57-82, n.d., 20 folders (Box 73-75)
- Speeches and other writings by HCD 1977, n.d. (Box 75)
- Clippings (Box 75)
- Seminar papers for Legal Philosophy taught by HCD 1969-70 (Box 75)
- Reprints of articles sent to HCD by the authors and, in some cases, annotated by him (Box 76)